{
    "questions": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "What is the most effective method for securing data on a lost or stolen laptop?",
        "options": {
          "A": "Implementing a Host-based firewall",
          "B": "Using a Strong administrator password",
          "C": "Using an Anti-malware software",
          "D": "Implementing Full disk encryption"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "In which of the given scenarios is it reasonable to anticipate some level of privacy?",
        "options": {
          "A": "Sharing a comment on a friend's social media page",
          "B": "Providing personal details on a school enrollment website",
          "C": "Commenting on a video-sharing platform",
          "D": "Sending emails and pictures to a close family member"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "What data type should a developer use to store an alphanumeric postal code in a variable?",
        "options": {
          "A": "Integer",
          "B": "String",
          "C": "Float",
          "D": "Boolean"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Which of the following is most similar to machine language?",
        "options": {
          "A": "Scripted language",
          "B": "Compiled language",
          "C": "Query language",
          "D": "Assembly language"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "What is the primary purpose of using a function in programming?",
        "options": {
          "A": "To hold a list of numbers.",
          "B": "To be divided into reusable components.",
          "C": "To define needed constant values.",
          "D": "To define variables to hold different values."
        },
        "correct_answer": "B"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Which option offers the fastest transfer rate when transferring a file across the network?",
        "options": {
          "A": "1001 Kbps",
          "B": "110 Mbps",
          "C": "1.22 Gbps",
          "D": "123 Mbps"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "A technician has been tasked with assigning an IP address to a newly acquired desktop computer. Which of the following represents a suitable IP address for the technician to assign?",
        "options": {
          "A": "127.0.0.1",
          "B": "172.16.2.189",
          "C": "192.168.257.1",
          "D": "255.255.255.0"
        },
        "correct_answer": "B"   
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "What is the most suitable computing device for a game developer who requires a system with robust and upgradeable specifications to accommodate the demands of game engine software?",
        "options": {
          "A": "Laptop",
          "B": "Server",
          "C": "Game console",
          "D": "Workstation"
        },
        "correct_answer": "D"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "A company needs multiple reports that analyze interconnected information from sales, inventory, marketing, and compensation data. What is the most suitable location for storing this data?",
        "options": {
          "A": "Flat file",
          "B": "Word processor",
          "C": "Database",
          "D": "Network share"
        },
        "correct_answer": "C"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "The computer user is downloading software from the Internet and observes the following at the end of the installation file: 'x86.exe'. Which of the following statements best conveys the meaning of 'x86.exe' in the installation file?",
        "options": {
          "A": "x86 only supports an installation on a 32-bit CPU architecture",
          "B": "x86 supports an installation on a 32-bit and a 64-bit CPU architecture",
          "C": "x86 only supports an installation on a 64-bit CPU architecture",
          "D": "x86 supports an installation on a 16-bit CPU architecture"
        },
        "correct_answer": "A"
      }
    ]
  }
  
